THE ROTTEN EGG HATCHES
HERBIVORE DRAMA CLUB
CARNIVORE DRAMA CLUB
[Bill] So... we got word from the Festival
of the Meteor Committee yesterday.
And, uh...
"The plan to segregate
carnivores and herbivores
between halves of the performance
clearly contradicts
our 'Live Together' theme,
our main deciding factor in this decision.
Unfortunately, we are unable to feature
your club at this year's festival."
- What? That's not fair.
- It really says that?
What a cruel thing. I can't believe it.
So that's it then. They're letting
a drama club tradition die.
How sad. And there's nothing we can do?
Uh... [sighs]
[Kai] Come on, Bill!
You can't be okay with this.
If we let them cancel the festival,
we'll never be able to face Louis again.
[sighs] You're right.
[Els] Wait a second.
None of this is Bill's fault.
[all sigh]
- [Juno] I don't blame Bill.
- [Kai] Guess it can't be helped.
- But it still sucks.
- Excuse me! Can I say something?
You got this.
I think maybe we made the wrong decision
about the drama club.
What do mean by that?
You remember how we took that vote,
whether we should split ourselves
into two separate clubs
or suspend activities entirely?
[Bill] Yeah. And we chose
to continue activities separately
while not forgetting our aim
of co-existence and co-prosperity.
You know, "living together"?
[scoffs] You'd think
they'd appreciate the effort.
It's not so bad. Sure we've got this wall,
but at least they won't shut us down.
[Kibi] Okay, but will there be a wall
to separate carnivores and herbivores
at the venue
for the Festival of the Meteor?
I seriously doubt it.
Why would they have one?
How can they tell us to live together,
but shut us down for integrating
the only way we can?
I mean, I figure the school
just doesn't want to take any more risks.
Safety issue. Anything can happen.
We know that.
[Els sighs]
[sighs] Okay, listen.
You all remember the accident.
I lost my arm completely.
[all gasp]
[Kibi] When I was in the hospital,
I thought about quitting drama club
and leaving school altogether.
Just seeing a carnivore
made me panic and freeze up.
I felt like I couldn't breathe.
[Tao sighs]
When I was recovering
after they reattached my arm,
I had to stay sitting up in bed,
just staring at my own hand for hours.
[mellow music playing]
The sun and the breeze
came through my window
and brushed up against me,
and very slowly, I started to get feeling
back in my hand.
That was really exciting.
I couldn't wait to touch something.
And I knew exactly who
I wanted to be there for it.
- My friend, Tao.
- [gasps softly]
My point is, it's not like I chose
to have such a fragile body.
Just like Tao didn't choose to be strong.
[Tao exhales]
When I came for that visit
and you asked me to touch your hand...
[sighs]
...I started to cry.
Because I knew
that was all way harder on you,
but, still, you considered my feelings.
And that's all it took to take down
the wall that formed between us.
[exhales softly]
It wasn't hard, because I know
who the real Tao is.
A fellow drama club member,
who was always on my side.
[Tao grunts softly]
I think Kibi is right.
We were mistaken.
We shouldn't have listened to the school
- and their idiotic rules.
- [Bill] Tao...
Separating ourselves,
not seeing, not touching.
That might give some of you
peace of mind, but not me!
Now that we've experienced
the dangerous issues
between both of our species,
we've more perspective on the matter.
Yeah, that's all well and good,
but we're not gonna get 'em to bend
on the festival.
It's already over.
No, it is not!
Just look around. We've overcome
way bigger obstacles than this.
Yeah, he's right.
Remember last year's festival?
When I heard that Louis had disappeared,
I thought we'd have to cancel outright,
but then Juno took charge
and it all worked out in the end.
Oh, Ellen.
That wasn't just me, it was all of us.
Right? It's literally that easy.
We pulled it off
because we were all together.
Exactly. We may all have
different positions on this,
but we know what we can accomplish
by working together.
So why stop now?
He's right, you know. We're unstoppable.
Yeah. Actors, sound crew,
lighting, the set design...
As long as everyone is committed
to their roles like any other production,
we can create a unified performance,
even with this wall!
He's right. It's not hard!
We'll just build a show
the festival committee can't turn down.
Whoa, Els, cool it!
Let's try again!
We'll talk to the committee right now.
- And the school!
- I don't know about that.
[Kai] Yes, you do.
You turn into a housecat
while we weren't looking?
- [Bill] Hey.
- Get it through your thick skull.
Louis choose you as the next president
for a reason.
That's true.
What do you want to do here, Bill?
[splutters]
[exhales] Well, I...
[grunts] Let's do it!
Leave negotiations with the school to me!
- [all cheer]
- [Ellen] That's our Bill!
All right! I'm all in too!
My dad always said,
"There's no nut that can't be cracked!"
You can't even crack a nut.
Hey, I'm going to get it one day.
Just wait.
JUNGLE THEATER
CLOSED TODAY
[Legoshi] Oh, boy.
This place? Really?
Hmm.
I have to assume that you've never been
to a strip show before.
[Legoshi] No, I never have.
Appetite and sexual desire
satisfied at once.
You can see how they're popular
among carnivores.
That's not why you brought me here, is it?
No, I want you to meet
one of the dancers who works here.
She is an okapi.
Herbivores work in the Black Market?
This young lady will be dancing
at Melon's masquerade party later tonight.
And you will be going in undercover
disguised as Haruo, her chaperone.
What? And you picked that name 'cause...
Melon is a male in his mid-twenties
to early-thirties.
The upper half of his face
is that of a gazelle,
but the rest is leopard, very distinctive.
Yeah, I'm sure, but how do we spot him
if he's wearing a mask?
You can leave finding him to me.
But I want you to take him down once I do.
Gohin always knew
how to hold his own in a fight.
I imagine he taught you well.
You really seem to know everything
about me.
Oh, and about your devouring record...
I can make that disappear,
wipe the slate clean.
Huh?
You still want to marry that rabbit, Haru,
isn't that the case?
Um, well, I...
- All right, see you at the party.
- Oh, what? We're not going together?
[yelps]
[suspenseful music playing]
[grunting]
I'll relay instructions through this.
[groans]
- Fine.
- [door opens]
- [Cosmo] Hey, are you Haruo?
- [door closes]
What?
Uh...
Oh. Yes, I am!
Wow, look at you. All business today, huh?
Huh?
[Yahya] And by the way, I've introduced
you to your charge for the evening.
You're a playboy type with a fascination
for underworld parties.
Act well your part, drama club boy.
- You know I only did lighting, right?
- Don't speak out loud!
[Legoshi] Oh!
[Yahya] And definitely don't mention
the investigation.
You'll put the ladies in danger.
Now look at my seat.
Put that on before you go inside.
- [Cosmo] Let's go.
- Uh, 'kay.
Uh, hold on, baby!
[softly] "Baby"? Really?
[exhales]
- [door opens]
- Hmm?
Oh, this is Luna.
Hey, gorgeous. Nice to meet ya!
Stop. Don't be weird.
Just be quiet, like a manager should.
Okay.
Don't bully him. Just get in already.
[engine revving]
Now, Haruo, don't think this means
you're invited to this party, okay?
Yeah, I know, that's fine.
- Will there be celebrities?
- Asking about the guests is prohibited.
This is a secret party
for the upper class.
Blow it, and you'll be out
before you can say "Jack Russell."
It'll be crazy fun, though.
Oh, yeah, fun doesn't
even begin to cover it.
I will warn you about one thing.
Anyone hands you a red juice,
just get rid of it.
That stuff will send a weakling like you
right over the edge in no time.
Over the edge?
What she's saying is,
your instincts will take control.
My instincts? Like, I'll want to eat
fresh meat, or what?
The types that come to these parties
have all long since passed that stage.
The carnivores at these events
have their impulses under control,
and, generally speaking,
the herbivores are less wary of us.
That's what makes these things
so much fun.
Carnivores and herbivores
truly feel equal.
It's liberation from the constraints
of polite society.
It's the ideal coexistence.
That said, there are impulses
far more terrifying
than the urge to eat a steak
every once in a while.
- Huh?
- [chuckles]
Yeah, apparently someone goes missing
at every one of these things.
[stutters] Ah!
So the red juice, is it like...
Is it some kind of drug?
Don't know. But you're not going to
touch it anyway, so who cares?
Now, get those horns on, and keep quiet.
Huh.
[yawns]
- Good evening.
- Thanks for working the door.
[groans]
God, I can hardly see in this thing.
Ow, it's pinching my ears too.
Uh, hey, what's up?
Nope, not you.
Oh, that's Haruo, the new chaperone.
- Ah, yeah?
- [Legoshi] Mmm.
Better know the password then.
[Legoshi] Huh?
Uh...
Come on, now. A hippo's skin...
[stammers] A hippo's... skin?
Nobody told me about this! What do I do?
[indistinct chatter]
[both] Cheers.
- [indistinct conversation]
- [light music playing]
[guests chattering]
[Yahya] I know Melon is here somewhere.
Gazelle horns...
the slender body of an herbivore...
the curved back muscles of a feline...
- Careful, that tickles.
- [giggles]
- You like it, though, don't you?
- Oh, you're such a bully.
[guest 2] You're adorable.
Your breasts are perfect.
[guest 1] It's my turn.
[chattering continues]
[Legoshi] So, how are we supposed
to find him in this crowd?
[Yahya] Legoshi, do you read me?
Yes, loud and clear.
And, hey, please tell me the passwords
in advance next time.
What? "A hippo's skin is sensitive"?
I told you that.
[Legoshi] No. No, you did not.
Well...
Well, no harm done.
Do you have eyes on Luna?
Yes, sir.
[Yahya] Do you see the horned male
watching her? He has a glass.
[Legoshi] Huh. Yeah.
[Yahya] Good.
Now look for the horned couple
embracing in front of the stage...
[Legoshi] Okay.
[Yahya] There's one more horned male
sitting at the bar.
- He hasn't moved.
- Ah. Yeah, I see him.
Melon is one of those three,
I'm sure of it.
Uh, then, how do we find out?
[Yahya] By removing their masks.
And how are we supposed to do that?
- Well, hello there, handsome.
- [Legoshi] Huh?
Care to join me for a little private time?
- [Legoshi] Uh... [chuckles nervously]
- Come on.
[both grunt]
[guest] You don't want to?
- Legoshi!
- [guest] Let's go.
[Legoshi chuckling]
Okay, okay. All right. You got me.
- [sighs heavily]
- [Legoshi and guest laughing]
To think that the Beastar's office
is higher up than the mayor's is.
- How foolish.
- What do you want?
Lately, devouring incidents among
younger beasts have been on the rise.
It seems that the suppressants made
by your company have lost their efficacy.
I have to wonder
how you're spending your subsidies.
Is that all you wanted to discuss?
How much do you know
about the Black Market?
It's an illicit market carnivores visit
to satisfy their needs,
their cravings to eat fresh meat.
It's a truly repulsive place.
It's said that the meat sold at the market
belonged to animals who died
in accidents or from disease.
But, in fact...
in the not-to-distant past,
innocent children
were being sold there in secret
as live bait. [grunts]
This catalogue contains records
of all those transactions.
LIVE BAIT CATALOGUE
And what came as the greatest shock to me,
is that carnivores weren't the only ones
buying live meat.
Can you imagine?
[paper rustles]
Here, for example.
This cute little fawn went
for a handsome price,
to another deer of all creatures!
It's hard not to wonder if they ate him.
[Ogma exhales]
Now, that was 15 years ago,
so if he were still alive,
I guess he'd be 18.
That's the same age
as your Louis, am I right?
Here's something funny.
I just remembered the Black Market
has a very popular fight club.
Their champion, Kyuu, is a young rabbit
who somehow managed
to escape this same live bait market.
She may even remember that little fawn.
Wish that we could ask her.
[sighs softly]
I plan to throw this in the shredder
when I finish my term.
I have no use for it.
It's just a relic of an unfortunate past.
There a point to this?
Matter of fact, there is one little thing
that I'm afraid I can only ask
of the head of the illustrious
Horns Conglomerate.
[both giggling]
- [female guest] Not there. You're so bad.
- [male guest chuckles]
[female guest giggling]
[sniffing]
[grunts]
- I thought I told you no.
- I didn't. I was just looking.
He said while he was elbow deep
in the cookie jar.
[Legoshi] Sorry. Uh...
Oh.
Herbivores really are beautiful creatures.
[yelps]
You better keep it in your pants, buddy.
- I can see your mask steaming up.
- Sorry. I wasn't-- [yelps]
[sighs]
It's so hard to breathe.
I feel like I'm going to die.
[exhales] Not to mention
I can't see a thing.
Eyes keep fogging up. Ow.
Who would like this?
[guest] Ain't it funny how a carnivore
can wear a mask with horns
and pretend to be an herbivore...
[inhales sharply] ...but herbivores
who are born with them
don't get to remove them? [scoffs]
Pretty unfair rule,
wouldn't you say? [scoffs]
[Legoshi] Huh? Oh, uh...
- I don't think it's that deep, buddy.
- [guest] Eh, you're right.
[zips pants]
Huh?
That smell...
Wait, that was him!
[panting]
[thrilling music playing]
It has to be him.
[panting]
[thudding]
Oh.
Such grace.
He's beautiful.
[panting]
[exclaiming]
Oh!
[whispering] Mr. Yahya. I found Melon.
Where is he now?
Security booth above the grid.
You can get up here from behind the bar.
Got it. Do not move in until I get there.
[Legoshi] Understood.
[Melon] Ladies and gentlemen,
tonight we'll be serving Melda,
a drink 100 times more potent
than our usual juice.
Sorry, only one per person,
but, please, enjoy.
[gasps]
[Melon] And the wolf sneaks away
from the pack
to pick off the helpless gazelle.
Only you're not...
You're not a pure gazelle, are you?
- Oh?
- I could smell it.
Bodily waste, it carries the smell
of whatever you ate last.
Your urine smelled of meat,
which wouldn't make any sense...
if you were an herbivore.
My, my. Nothing gets past
a canine's sense of smell, does it?
Move!
So, what do you want?
To arrest you.
- Well, not me, I just--
- Arrest me? For what?
I haven't done anything.
Uh... you're suspected
of the mass slaughter of large herbivores
and illegal organ trafficking.
Was that it?
Anyway, my partner will be here soon.
Hmm... You mean the horse?
Yeah, he might be indisposed
for some time.
But that's all right.
What do you say we have us a little chat
until he trots in?
- I kind of thought you'd run.
- [groans]
Again, I haven't done anything wrong!
[inhales sharply] Besides,
I'd love to get to know you better
since you're not a pure wolf, are you?
- How...
- [laughs] I knew it!
Oh, this isn't really fair, is it?
I should take off my mask too.
[grunts]
Ah!
[Legoshi] It's like...
watching my own offspring hatching.
[snaps]
Um, how did you know about me?
That I'm mixed?
Well, first of all, you're much too big
to be a regular gray wolf,
and, second of all, you can't seem to hide
your incredibly deep interest in me.
- That's not what I...
- What are you mixed with?
No, don't tell me.
It's definitely not feline.
- Ooh, maybe a kangaroo.
- Komodo dragon, actually.
[laughs] Really? [laughs] No way.
Your parents were freaky.
Well, no, it's my maternal grandfather.
Wait. [splutters]
Why am I blabbing away like this
to someone I don't even know?
Hmm. Grandfather.
Well, my heart certainly goes out
to your poor mother. Tell her I said so.
She's dead.
She killed herself, uh,
when I was 12 years old.
[inhales] Oh, my.
I've had it pretty rough too,
my friend. I get it.
I mean, just look at this party.
Carnivores and herbivores
all over the world
long to be freed
from the barriers between species,
and here, they can drink and dance
and do just that.
But, even that's a luxury
that we don't get.
When you're mixed, you have no species
or comrades to speak of.
You're just a half-baked freak of nature.
Take that back. My mother was mixed,
but she was not a freak.
Oh, but she was, and that's precisely why
she killed herself.
[Legoshi] Hmm.
A mixed beast
will always be considered a thing.
Wait. What do you mean by that?
Exactly what it sounds like.
This society constantly claims
that it celebrates
closeness between carnivores
and herbivores.
[inhales sharply] So it's quite strange
that whenever a child is born
from that union,
it's an abomination.
That's not--
I don't think of you that way.
I think you're beautiful.
You're not an abomination.
[scoffs] Ugh, don't tell me you're one
of those sensitive, sentimental types.
- Huh?
- [laughs]
There's got to be more inside of you
than that, right?
Come on, loosen up. Tell me a joke.
[chuckles nervously]
No, I'm not good at stuff like that.
In that case,
I got one you're going to love.
[suspenseful music playing]
To think that the old stallion...
Sorry, the world-renowned Beastar,
would recruit such a young kid
to send here in his stead...
[laughs maniacally]
Quite the little prank you pulled.
You got me good.
[growls]
But now, it's my turn.
So don't touch that dial, folks,
or you'll miss the big finish.
[Legoshi breathing heavily]
- [gun cocks]
- Legoshi!
- [muffled gunshot]
- [Legoshi groaning]
[Legoshi spluttering]
That was the setup.
[laughs maniacally]
And now for the punchline!
[all] Cheers!
[guests screaming]
[closing theme song playing]
♪ Just like a new melody ♪
♪ I don't want to live without it ♪
♪ You give me the strength inside ♪
♪ Some things aren't meant to be ♪
♪ You say it like you know ♪
♪ But I really want you ♪
♪ I want you to see it the way I do ♪
♪ 'Cause every time I think about you ♪
♪ My heartbeat goes a-risin' ♪
- ♪ And I just want to feel like this ♪
- ♪ Run, run, run ♪
- ♪ Till I... ♪
♪ Till I die ♪
♪ There's nothing
That can beat like this ♪
♪ Faster as I close my eyes ♪
- ♪ Just want to feel like this ♪
- ♪ Run, run, run ♪
- ♪ Till the... ♪
♪ Till the night ♪
♪ Now as long as you are here by my side ♪
♪ Run, run, run ♪
♪ I keep walking on ♪
♪ Walking on, on, walking on, on ♪
- ♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
- ♪ Walking on, on, walking on, on ♪
- ♪ Run, run, run ♪
- ♪ I keep walking on ♪